ROHANSINGH

Software Developer

- rohansingh8382@gmail.com
- +91-6392278807
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohansingh0070/
- https://github.com/iamjerry07

Professional Summary:

Experienced Developer specializing in Node.js, and MongoDB. Committed to delivering top-notch web applications that prioritize user experience and scalability. Skilled in backend system design, and structured databases. Collaborative team player with a track record of driving projects from concept to completion. Stay up-to-date emerging technologies and industry best practices.

Skills

- Backend Technologies: Node.js,
 Next.js, JavaScript, Express.js, Redis,
 OpenAPI, TypeScript
- Version Control: Git, GitLab
- Cloud Services: AWS S3
- Database: MongoDB (NoSQL)
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows
- Other: DSA

Education

B.Tech.

KIET Group of Education, Ghaziabad 2016 – 2020

Hobbies

- Photography Music

Experience

1. Software Developer, NSSPL India

Sep 2023 - Present

I'm a skilled backend developer at NSSPL, specializing in Node.js, Next.js, and MongoDB to create robust and efficient web applications.

2. Backend Developer, Alphics Tech

Jun 2023 – Aug 2023

Elevated skills, excelled in Govt. Project. Demonstrated expertise, pivotal role. Effective collaboration, invaluable insights. Meaningful contribution, ready for new challenges.

3. Backend Developer, Superminds IT

Gurgaon, Aug 2022 - May 2023

Backend developer having experience of Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, MongoDB, JavaScript, and more. Successfully delivered 3 projects collaborating with team members. Strong problem-solving skills and attention to detail.

4. Backend Trainee, FunctionUP

Jan 2022 – July 2022

Learned backend development at FunctionUp bootcamp for 7 months, becoming proficient in Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, MongoDB, and JavaScript. Worked hard and was promoted to TA.

Self-Projects

1. E-Commerce Clone (Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB):

Developed a Flipkart-inspired e-commerce platform, emphasizing backend expertise.

2. Blogging Platform (Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB):

Created a user-friendly blog-sharing website for content creation and consumption.

3. Book Inventory Management (Typescript):

Designed a TypeScript-based system for efficient book cataloging and organization.